<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Workshops on Talks</title><link>https://speaking.moficodes.dev/workshops/</link><description>Recent content in Workshops on Talks</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 11:00:24 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://speaking.moficodes.dev/workshops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Build your First/Next REST API with Go</title><link>https://speaking.moficodes.dev/workshops/rest-api-with-go/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 11:00:24 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://speaking.moficodes.dev/workshops/rest-api-with-go/</guid><description>Pitch If you have been around a computer for long enough you probably are familiar with the term API maybe even REST API. But what are they really and why we in the Go community care about REST API? In this talk I will try to go over all you need to know to build your first or next REST API in Go.
Description Go is a language heavily used for web api building.</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes: The Second Week</title><link>https://speaking.moficodes.dev/workshops/k8s-second-week/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 11:50:21 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://speaking.moficodes.dev/workshops/k8s-second-week/</guid><description>Pitch If you are someone who is trying to learn how to use Kubernetes you probably already know the high level overview. There are great resources for it already. We are gonna talk about the second week stuff. The ones intro tutorials usually miss and advance tutorials gloss over.
Description Kubernetes is probably the de-facto container orchestrator for most people using container orchestrators. There is a huge demand for it as well as a lot of interest among people to learn Kubernetes.</description></item><item><title>From App Idea to K8s</title><link>https://speaking.moficodes.dev/workshops/from-app-idea-to-k8s/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 11:01:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://speaking.moficodes.dev/workshops/from-app-idea-to-k8s/</guid><description>Pitch With Docker and k8s you can go from an idea to a production app in hours. Lets take a look how that works in practice. From writing our app to containerizing it to getting it to be available for the entire world to access. Will also look at some sane best practices along the way.
Description Developers want to build applications. So how do we get our app out there in the real world?</description></item></channel></rss>